Preliminary Inventory of the Vladimir D. Pastuhov Papers, 1885-1968
Hoover Institution Archives
Vladimir D. Pastuhov Papers,
1885-1968
67023
Pastuhov, Vladimir D., 1898-
64 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize box, 3 album boxes, 1 envelope (33.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, interviews, maps, photographs, and printed matter, relating to the investigation of the Japanese incursion into Manchuria in 1931.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1967.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
China.; China--Economic conditions--1912-1949.; China--Foreign relations--Japan.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; Japan.; Japan--Economic conditions--1918-1945.; Japan--Foreign relations--China.; Japan--Politics and government--1912-1945.; Manchuria--Economic conditions.; Manchuria--History--1931-1945.; Manchuria--Politics and government.; Lytton, Victor Alexander George Robert Bulwer-Lytton, 2d earl of, 1876-; League of Nations. Commission of Enquiry into the Manchurian Question.
Container List
- "Shanghai Incident" (Box 1)
  - Letters from G. W. Sheppherd concerning the future of Shanghai - whether Chinese should have the right to tax residents, projects to turn over municipal government to Chinese, etc., 1932
  - League of Nations - Reports of the Committee of Inquiry sent up at Shanghai, Anti-Japanese boycott, 1932
  - Valuation of damages and losses to railway properties during the recent Shanghai crisis - The Nanking-Shanghai Line and the Shanghai-Kangchow-Ningpo Line. Destruction by Japanese troops, 1932
  - Telegram from British Minister at Shanghai to Foreign Office Committee of Inquiry, 1932
  - "Shanghai," report
  - "Documents relative to the Shanghai Incident"
  - "Shanghai War Pictorials No. 1," Chinese publication
  - "Shanghai Incident - Facts ascertained up to February 7, 1932"
  - Japan's Undeclared War on Shanghai. Published by Chinese Chamber of Commerce, Shanghai
  - Official documents relating to Japan's undeclared war in Shanghai
  - "The Japanese Attack on Shanghai." Kuomintang publication
  - "Shanghai Incident - Facts ascertained up to February 28, 1932"
  - "Shanghai Incident - Facts ascertained up to March 22, 1932
- "China-Japanese Boycott" (Box 2)
  - "The Boycott in China," prepared by the Japan-China Economic Association, Tokyo
  - "Memorandum on Boycotts and Japanese Interest in China," by A. Pelt
  - Questions to be directed by the Special Commission of the League of Nations to the Chinese government concerning Japanese charges against that government
  - Outlines of 9 boycotts
  - "The Boycott - Is it War? World Interest in Idea Quickened by China's Use of it in Combatting Japanese Influence." Reprint from Washington Star
  - "Memorandum on the Boycott"
  - "Anti-Japanese Activities in Peiping (March 5, 1932)"
  - "Conditions of Anti-Japanese Agitation in Peiping at the End of October, 1931"
  - "Bombing of the Naval Attache's Office and Publication of Irreverent Articles by 'Peping Chen Pao' and 'Leader'"
  - "Verbal Statement for Mr. Yans, Councillor of the Japanese Legation"
  - "The Anti-Japanese Boycott Movement in China (From October, 1931 to January, 1932)"
  - "Statement relating to the anti-Japanese movement in China, 1931-1932"
  - "Questions on Boycott to Japanese Chamber of Commerce in Shanghai"
- "The Harbin Relief Committee on Russian Emigrants." Reports to the Commission of Inquiry of the League of Nations on the situation of Russian emigres in Manchuria, including petitions and correspondence (Box 3)
- "League of Nations" #1 (Box 4)
  - "Covenant of the League of Nations," 1919
  - Records of sessions of the League of Nations, September-October 1936, September-October, 1935
- "League of Nations" #2. Records, 1935-1936 (Box 5)
- "League of Nations" #3 (Box 6)
  - Records of the Special Committee to study the constitution and practice and procedure of League Committees, 1935
  - List of members of the Committees of the League of Nations, 1934
  - Report to the Special Committee to study League committees, 1935
  - Minutes of the 91st Session (Extraordinary) of the Council, 1936
  - Response of the governments of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania to the circular letter 170, 1934
  - "Supply and Utilization of Information: Relations with International Organizations," 1934
  - League of Nations, committees (Box 7-8)
- Lytton Commission
  - General (Box 9-13)
  - Establishment of (Box 14)
  - Maps (Box 15)
  - Minutes (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Reports (Box 18)
  - Salt revenue (Box 19)
- Manchuria
  - General (Box 20-21)
  - Document and Analyses (Box 22)
  - Interviews and Documents (Box 23-29)
  - Newspapers and Magazines (Box 30-35)
  - Pamphlets (Box 36-42)
- Miscellaneous (Box 43)
- Mulxden Incident (Box 44)
- Press Clippings
  - Japanese (Box 45)
  - Japanese and Chinese (Box 46-48)
  - International and League of Nations Official Documents (Box 49-55)
- Tientsin (Box 56-58)
- Incremental materials (Box 59-69)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.